BOYS'
BASKETBALL
TEAM
Wrong... correct... wrong...
ANSWER
And wrong.
I've finished grading all of the tests.
And the results?
It's unfortunate, but...
Every single one of you...
...actually got a passing grade!
What the hell is "unfortunate" about that?!
Oops, sorry about that. What I meant to say was,
"It's my pleasure to announce!"
That being said, please don't get too relaxed
about the midterms.
All I did was check them to give us an idea.
My grading might be 2 or 3 points off
from the actual results.
That's hardly gonna make any difference.
It will because you guys are
just barely passing as it is!
Well... I'll acknowledge that
they've put in the effort.
After all, this lot has only managed
single-digit grades up until now.
With all their progress recently,
it would be nice to see a win tomorrow.
Of course! We've totally got this in the bag!
Everybody here is in it to win it.
I hope our reward is sushi this time.
Sushi, hell yeah!
Quit begging for a free
meal after every damn game!
All right! This is our last practice sesh!
Let's throw everything we've got into it!
Right!
Ahiru no Sora
Undiscovered Talent
Did you see the tourney bracket?
Our first opponent is gonna be Kuzu High!
What? Does Kuzu High even
have a basketball team?
They're new this year, aren't they?
Ugh. Isn't that the school with
a team full of delinquents?
Well, at least we know they
probably suck at the game.
Guess that means we're gonna
glide through the first round!
The big problem for us are the teams who come after.
Both Saijo and Shinmaruko are in our bracket, right?
Oh yeah, isn't Shinmaruko the team
from the Kanto tourney that- Ow!
It's impossible to know
the outcome of a match beforehand.
Quit belittling our opponents
before we even play them.
Oh. Sorry, Captain Takahashi!
W-we won't do it again!
Required Training For All
Running - 5 Minutes
Stretching
Slides - Full Court 5 Times
Squats - Full Court 5 Times
Sprints - x 100
No Slacking
Have you done your warmups?
N-not yet!
Get them done fast.
Huh? Senpai, isn't that popsicle...?
This? I found it in the freezer.
Because it's mine, I put it there!
Oh, my bad. I'll pay you back 50 yen later.
But it cost me 100 yen!
There he goes again.
Just when I think he's doing a solid job as leader,
he goes and acts all aloof like that.
Doesn't even look nervous.
But that's a good thing.
It's part of what makes
our Captain who he is.
'Sup?!
Good arf-ternoon, dawgs.
Hey, Kojima!
Is your leg injury doing better now?
It's doing just purr-fect.
Don't bother trying to fool us,
we know that you tore a ligament.
If I miss out on this tournament,
then my High School basketball career is over.
I don't want to have any regrets.
Noooo!
You're on the bench for now.
But no need to worry,
I'll get us through at least the first 3 games.
What a wimp! Can't even go all the way!
Oh yeah?! Take this!
Hey, did you know?
When Takahashi and Kojima joined
the basketball team here,
they were the only 2 members.
Huh?!
They spent every day
of their freshman year playing 1-on-1.
Then in their sophomore year,
some others finally joined,
but that only brought them up to 5 members.
So apparently they lost
every match they played.
Seriously? That's crazy, considering how awesome
Takahashi is on the court...
Well, you gotta remember we're in
the same region as Saijo and Kitasumi.
Ever since we joined the team this year,
it was like everything had finally come together,
but then in our last game,
Kojima ended up injuring his leg...
Hey, you freshmen.
Uh, yessir!
Who was in charge of mopping the court today?
Th-that would be us, sir!
Do it again!
Man, Kashiwagi really terrifies me!
Yeah, he's seriously the only
senior I just can't deal with!
I don't think I've ever seen him
actually mop the court even once!
But Takashi and the other
seniors do it all the time!
Just imagine this team if he wasn't around...
Shut up! He'll hear you!
We're starting! Hurry it up!
Yessir!
Freshmen! I expect louder cheering today.
Tanaka, get your foot off the line.
Shinjo...!
FIGHT!
Uh, hello? Nanao?
I just wanted to confirm
some details about tomorrow.
First, could you tell me what
I need to bring with me?
Right, okay. So then,
you'll bring our uniforms.
Yep. I think you've got all you need.
You're more of a worrywart
than I would have expected, Kurumatani.
Uh, yeah. It's cuz I somehow
always manage to forget stuff.
Tomorrow is finally the
big day. Are you nervous?
Huh? No! Not at all!
Make sure you go to bed
as early as possible tonight, okay?
Right.
Uh, so we're meeting at
8:00 am tomorrow, right?
I just told you that a minute ago.
Let's give it our all.
Yeah.
Okay, goodnight.
Yeah, nighty night.
I better check just one more time!
Hello? Kite?
I just wanna confirm about tomorrow...
Why are you calling THIS late, dumbass?!
I thought your game didn't start 'til noon.
Aren't you leaving just a tad too early?
I'm leaving early so I can go to school
and get some practice in.
You'll wear yourself out
before the game even starts, then!
It'll be okay!
I'm off!
I tried, but I couldn't sleep a wink!
This is the first time in my life...
...that I've ever been so hyped up!
The sun is so bright this morning.
How beautiful...
That... threw me for a loop!
That's right, today is...
You've really grown so much
in the time I haven't seen you.
Do your best out there... Sora!
What the-?
Oh... hey, Tinytown.
What are all of you guys doing here?!
Don't tell me that you never
actually left yesterday...
Nah, we went home for a bit,
but... we just couldn't sleep at all.
So we decided to try and do some extra practice on our shots...
but then all of a sudden it was morning.
I'm dead tired...
Yeah, you said it...
The world is turning white...
This is an absolute disaster!
You see? I told you they'd be here.
I don't believe this.
Chiaki?! Did something happen to you?!
It's 6:00 in the morning!
When it comes to trips or events,
I'm always up bright and early.
Don't tell me that both of you also...
We were up playing games all night.
That means our team is in the
worst condition right now!
You can go in before me, beanstalk.
Huh?
I don't want them thinking we're all buddy-buddy by
showing up at the exact same time.
Thanks. Good to know you care so much.
Wha-?
Ouch...
I... I'm so sorry...
You brainless moron!
We'd be screwed if you went and injured me right before our match!
I kinda wish she had.
Just you wait, Mom.
I'm definitely coming to see you soon!
FIGHT WITH
ALL YOUR MIGHT
Whoa, teams are already practicing.
Must be the ones competing first today.
Ow! Watch it, punk!
Oh... sorry about that.
NAKANE
Well, those guys are clearly
good at basketball...
Yeah and based just on looks,
we're leaving the exact opposite impression...
Yahoo!
WHAT THE HELL DO YOU THINK YOU'RE DOING?!
I, uh, I'm really sorry!
I honestly dunno what's
gotten into me right now.
Yeah, man. I feel ya.
What's wrong with you, Mokichi?
It's my anemia... I'm gonna pass out...
Then go home, stupid!
You guys are as lively as ever.
Yo.
Hey, it's Tokiwa! And the
other guys from Maru High!
Sheesh, the first round of a tournament
isn't anything to jump for joy over.
Just watching you is
already making me cringe.
Win 2 and you get to play us.
We're expecting to see you there.
Count on it!
That reminds me, Chiba.
How are you guys fairing in the Kanto Tournament?
If I remember right, it's held alongside
the inter-high prelims, yeah?
That's right. We just played
a game earlier this week.
But we lost in the quarterfinals.
It's unbelievable, we can't even get ourselves
in the top 5. Just pathetic.
Except, the opposing team was
a well-known inter-high favorite.
I'd say we just had bad luck.
That doesn't make them unbeatable.
We'll get our revenge the next time around.
We're scheduled to play the very last game today,
so we'll be having fun watching your match in the meantime.
Shoo! Git!
So even Maru High couldn't
be the prefectural reps.
We've got a long road to the top.
Those guys are just small
fries, if you ask me.
Long time no see... my friends.
Oh, it's just Farto Kabachi.
My name is TARO Kabachi!
C'mon, let's get warmed up.
Hey! Don't just ignore me!
Actually, thinking about it,
Kitasumi isn't even playing here...
Huh?
Yeah, well, you see...
I wanted to come and make sure
that Nao didn't forget about me.
So, you're gonna die soon?
Bye-bye.
Nobody is dying, dammit!
Our game is getting ready to start!
Where the hell are you?!
I'm gonna make you guys
regret this! Stupid jerks!
From what I hear, Kuzu High
just barely formed their basketball team.
According to our coach, a number
of their players are complete amateurs.
I kinda feel an affinity
for them, knowing that.
It's starting to push my excitement level
through the woof!
Well, since we're both bottom
tier teams I hope this'll be-
Don't be stupid, we're more experienced.
We kept pushing for those 3 years,
just so that we could get to this tournament.
Bottom tier or not, anybody playing high school
basketball has dreams of going to the inter-high.
And I...
...want to blaze a trail for this team.
Don't start laughing at me, freshmen.
W-we would never think of it!
I have dreams just like you said!
Please take us to the inter-high!
We're counting on you!
You guys...
Don't phrase it like that, be more positive and say,
"Let's all get there together."
You guys are gonna be playing out there, too.
We've got high hopes for all of you.
Y-yessir!
Okay! Let's do this!
Everything starts by winning the first game.
Don't let your guard down just because they seem weak!
Let's get out there and win this thing!
Yeah!
KUZURYU
I'm so glad I made it back in time.
I can't believe I forgot the jerseys after I
brought them all the way to school this morning!
These are sick!
You've got it on backwards, dummy!
And these are your new
t-shirts for practice, look!
Momoharu even came up
with a really cool design for the backside!
Don't you guys think they
all turned out really good?
DRAGON BALL
Oh, it says "Ryu Kyu." I get it.
You took the "Ryu" from Kuzuryu.
Huh? You've got it totally wrong, you idiot.
This is what "basket ball" looks like
when you write it with proper kanji.
I think the word you actually
wanted was "Rou Kyu."
BASKET BALL
That's the kanji for basket
that I remember... yeah.
DRAGON BALL
That's fine! It's all
good if we understand it!
Everyone will figure out that it's meant to be
the Ryu from Kuzuryu!
That's the end of the 2nd quarter!
Sweet, let's get moving!
The teams playing in the next game
get to practice on the court during halftime.
Shinjo...!
Fight! Yeah!
Wow... those guys are really pumped up.
Any team giving off energy like that
has got to be tough to beat...
We sure as hell aren't gonna win
if you let them psych you out now.
I know you guys have more guts than that.
He's right.
A'ight, boys! Time for us to get out there
and make some noise!
Raise the roof!
Did the lead up time to a match
always make me this nervous?
Dammit! I'm a real sad sack of shit.
What's up with that tiny kid?
Did they accidentally let an
elementary schooler in here?
There's no way that kid even
reaches 160 centimeters.
Totally, he's gotta be a sub or something.
Though... is it just me
or has he not missed a single shot?
What's going on?
They're saying there's an
amazing shooter down there.
Oh sweet, Shinjo's playing next!
They've got some solid players on their team.
An afro and a pompadour?
What's up with that team of weirdos?
Looks like it'll be an entertaining matchup.
Let's go check it out for a bit!
Dammit...
You better not be thinking
about playing today.
Give me a break.
You don't have to harp on me
every chance you get, dude!
I get it! Order received, Captain!
I'm just gonna
sit here and watch quietly from the bench!
Okay! Fine!
But one condition...
I get to beat the shit
outta you if we lose this.
Sure. Feel free.
That's the end of the game!
Alright!
Okay so, Chiaki, Kurumatani,
Natsume, Yasuhara, and Momoharu.
The five of you will be our starting lineup.
We're not going to be sloppy
and wait it out like we did before.
We're putting our best foot
forward right from the start.
Chiaki, I want you to be as aggressive as possible
by getting under the basket.
If the flow of the game dictates it,
feel free to change positions with Kurumatani.
Sure, leave it to me.
This is our first battle. Let's
tear it up out there, Yasuhara.
You got it!
Attention. The second match on court A,
Kuzuryu High School vs. Shinjotowa Academy
will now begin.
SHI-N-JO! SHI-N-JO! SHI-N-JO! SHI-N-JO!
It's all you, Yukio.
Okay.
This guy is like a damn skyscraper!
Why are all the guys I
go up against so huge?!
Well, this guy isn't that
imposing compared to Chiba.
A difference of 7 or 8 centimeters
sure as hell ain't gonna stop me!
I gotta get my nerves under control!
This a tournament, which means we're out
if we lose even once!
Yo, Yasuhara! You're facing the wrong way!
This is bad. Everyone's a nervous wreck!
I bet scoring the first basket
would snap them out of it.
But I can't expect that to happen
with our Captain like that.
It's a damn shame, since they're all usually
really smooth on the court.
Shit! I screwed up the timing!
Pass it here!
C'mon! Let's make this first one count!
We're playing man-to-man defense!
Get moving, Yasuhara! Don't
forget who you're guarding!
It's #7!
Don't get yourself in a panic, Yanagihara.
Just do it like we practiced.
I've taken the court during
plenty of games, so I'm okay!
Please rest assured and let
me take over for Kojima!
Remind me, aren't you friends
with that #4 down there, Chiba?
Yep. We were on the same
junior basketball team together.
Back then, we both got
assigned to be point guard.
It's because of Takahashi
that I hardly ever got put in a real game.
Oh?
Make sure you watch closely, Tokiwa.
There's more undiscovered talent in this world
than you can shake a stick at.
Not every player out there is
just plain lucky like we are.
He got by!
So fast... despite being so tall?!
Dammit! His good looks pissed
me off enough already!
Right down the middle! He's like a flash!
He's just trying to pull defenders off
and pass to the big guy!
It's so obvious!
Right on the mark!
Nice! It's all mine! It'll be a turnover!
He stopped?! In the middle of it?!
Screen!
Switch, Yasu!
The first basket!
They're so awesome!
That was smooth...
I'm starting to think this
team might be really good...
Amazing.
They were all so calm and
recovered really fast.
This is a team that's really in control!
Hey, bro.
Nice job, Yanagihara!
All right! Let's keep this up!
Defense! Defense! Defense! Defense!
What is happening?
We just barely started...
but I can hardly breathe...
That doesn't look good.
They got overwhelmed.
The other team will run away with it.
Okay, time for defense!
Right!
We'll shut them dow-
What the-? Was that a gust of wind?
Hey, Ref.
He hit me just now.
Th-the basket counts! One free-throw!
Huh? What just happened?
He took it all the way alone.
Well damn, this is a shocker.
Another trove of undiscovered talent...
...was waiting to be found
right there, of all places.
That... was totally nuts.
I'm so glad he's on OUR team...
I've seen any number of players
who could be considered good...
But... this guy is...
...way beyond even that level.
I'll give you two minutes.
Take that time to shake off your nerves.
You better start getting used to this,
or you'll waste precious stamina.
That's Kite for you.
He's always there to step up
at the most crucial times.
It's incredible.
Smug jackass. But damn if he ain't reliable!
Hey. I'm totally fine, just so you know.
I wasn't talking about you, bro.
Here they come!
A'ight! We're on defense!
Let's stop 'em cold!
Ahiru no Sora
Next time: "Rush and Rush."